LIUDMILA ORLOVA

DATA ANALYST ENTRY LEVEL BERLIN

lussie.orlova@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I'm looking for a position as a Data Analyst. I have great experience in IT and web development. I've worked as IT project manager for 10 years with a team of up to 15 persons.

I have a great desire to develop my skills in Data Analysis and Data Science. I enjoy searching and finding data, systematizing everything around me. I get excited looking for patterns. In the future I'd like to build and test various hypotheses.

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Student

August 2022 - Present

I am studying for the Statistics and Data Science MicroMasters program online at MIT. I accomplished the first part with excellent results (96%) and gained a scholarship award.

I have several small projects and experiments:

https://github.com/Lussie/Sandbox https://github.com/Lussie/Games

Solved problems on Rosalind: https://rosalind.info/users/Lussie/

Senior Project Manager

ADV web-engineering

July 2014 - November 2020 (6 years 5 months)

Moscow, Russia

I was working as project manager in development of portals on the base of Microsoft Sharepoint with many customizations. I had a team of 12: backend and frontend developers, business analytics, Q&A. Three of them were in a remote team. In some cases I worked with outsource teams.

Main projects:

- Leroy Merlin (intranet, social network). Results: development of an API for mobile app, design, development and implementation of social network.
- Invitro (personal online cabinets for medical offices). Results: design and development of online cabinets from the beginning till the implementation, successful integration with data bus for exchanging data with different IT-modules.
- Megafon (unified knowledge base). Results: deep analytics of all processes of call-center, identification of needs and existing problems.

Other projects: Nizhfarm, GroupM, TSUM (maintenance, implementation of new modules).

Technologies used: C#, .NET, Redis, HTML5.

Project Manager

SmartMedia

February 2013 - June 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Moscow, Russia

Full-cycle management of website development (promo-sites, corporate sites, web-portals, social networks): presale, design, markup, programming, testing, launching.

SKILLS

Python

SQL

Git

Probability Theory

COURSES ACCOMPLISHED

SQL,

Python Programming,

Workshop in Mathematics and Python,

Basics of Statistics,

Combinatorics,

Introduction to Calculus,

Introduction to Databases,

Version Control with Git

EDUCATION

Financial Academy under the Government of the Russian Federation

Finance and Crediting (1998 - 2003)

PERSONAL QUALITIES

- good learning ability,
- aspiration to new knowledge,
- responsibility,
- communication skills,
- attention to details,
- ability to work in a team.

I like to manage versatile tasks and to gain new knowledge.

LANGUAGES

Russian - native

English - advanced